Dalia Abdulelah

Application Engineer

Saudi Arabia • +966562044655 daliaasq@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/daliaasq

Personal Details:

08/09/1998 • Female • Saudi Arabian

Organized computer information system and tech-savvy with commitment to excellence and broad understanding of information systems. Progressive experience in delivering exceptional assistance in design, and execution of projects based on customer needs, time and budget. Instrumental in collaboration, self-driven and promoting excellent problem solving and self-management skills. Thrives to learn, grow, and excel in technology; bilingual in English & Arabic.

Interests

- Cloud Computing
- Web Development
- Virtualization
- UI/UX
- Artificial Intelligence

- Machine Learning
- Mobile Development
- Cyber Security
- System Analysis
- Internet of Things (IoT)

- Data Visualization
- Networking
- Project Management
- Data Analysis
- Data Science

Career Experience

Tuwaiq Academy, Riyadh, Saudi ArabiaPython Application development Bootcamp

April 2023 - Present

Honeywell, Dhahran Techno Valley, Saudi Arabia Application Engineer Intern

June 2022 - November 2022

An application engineer who oversees deploying, securing, and configuring applications and mobility solutions, standardize a data collection template to create a generalized version for collecting design inputs from clients and eases analyzing the collected data. Set up a CPM server and a domain controller, create virtual machines, and install Windows server 2019 and active directory services. Create a hierarchy of organizational units and group policy objects. Set up a virtual network that interfaces the CPM server and the domain controller. Configure the NTP server to synchronize the timing of the CPM server with the domain controller to maintain the trust relationship. Install the latest firmware and MS office upgrades. Led FAT with the customer to confirm compliance with their cybersecurity standards.

- Configured operation management application.
- Assisted in standardizing a data collection template.
- Set up a domain controller and configured a set of OUs & GPOs.
- Performed security hardening on a server to ensure compliance with SABIC's cyber policy standards.
- Involved in a Factory Acceptance Test and led the cybersecurity tests with the client (SABIC).
- Assisted in updating a group of Remote Terminal Units (RTU) & observed the loop testing activity.

Saudi Digital Academy, Online

August 2021 - November 2021

Cloud Computing Bootcamp Trainee

Worked with Google Cloud Platform (GCP) to design, architect, and deploy the solution to the cloud.

- Exceeded goals through effective task prioritization and great work ethics.
- Participated in continuous improvement by generating suggestions, and engaging in problem-solving activities to support teamwork.
- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.

Ministry of Communications and Information Technology, Online

June 2020 - August 2020

Operations and Maintenance Internship

- Worked remotely in a virtual environment to configure and maintain a networked computer system, including hardware, system software, and applications.
- Upgraded, install, and configure new hardware and software.
- Created detailed and organized weekly reports for my supervisor.

Education

Bachelor of Science — Computer Information Systems

Imam Abdulrahman bin Faisal University, Dammam, Saudi Arabia.

Recognitions

- Cloud Computing Champion of the Week Saudi Digital Academy.
- Graduated with a second honorary degree College of Computer Science & Information Technology.
- Certificate of excellence College of Computer Science & Information Technology.

Technical Proficiencies

C++ | Java | HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Python | Virtualization | VMware | MySQL | Android Development | Axure RP | Figma | Windows Server | Active Directory | PowerShell | CMD | Weka | Advanced Excel | MS Office | XML | JSON | Data Analysis | Data Processing | AWS | GCE | Azure | Alibaba Cloud.

Personal Projects

• Tiptech website (Alibaba cloud hackathon).

Tiptech is a website that provides fast and easy tipping solution, empowered using Alibaba cloud services to be deployed and managed. the website targeting luxuries organizations and giving them the ability to manage the process, this done by provide the workers ID card with NFC technology, allowing the customer fast access to the website when he bring his mobile close to the worker's card to rate and pay.

IoT based School Bus Tracking System (Final Year Project).

Developed a tracking website for the school administration and an Android application for the bus driver and the student's legal guardian, to track the location of buses, and the attendance of students through scanning QR code attached to their IDs. The system sends real-time notification to the student's legal guardian with updated status.